Every fairy tale has a dark side.
Fifty Shades Darker is a drama, romance film directed by James Foley.
When a wounded Christian Grey tries to entice a cautious Ana Steele back into his life,
she demands a new arrangement before she will give him another chance.
As the two begin to build trust and find stability, shadowy figures from Christian’s past start
to circle the couple, determined to destroy their hopes for a future together.
Anastasia Steele, played by Dakota Johnson.
Christian Grey, played by Jamie Dornan.
Jack Hyde, played by Eric Johnson.
Kate Kavanagh, played by Eloise Mumford.
Leila, played by Bella Heathcote.
Mia Grey, played by Rita Ora.
Fifty Shades Darker is a 2017 American erotic romantic drama film directed
by James Foley and written by Niall Leonard, based on E.
James's 2012 novel of the same name.
Produced by Michael De Luca Productions and Trigger Street Productions, and distributed by Universal Pictures, it is the
second installment in the Fifty Shades film series and the sequel to the 2015 film Fifty Shades of Grey.
The film stars Dakota Johnson and Jamie Dornan as Anastasia Steele and Christian Grey, respectively, with Eric Johnson, Eloise
Mumford, Bella Heathcote, Rita Ora, Luke Grimes, Victor Rasuk, Kim Basinger, and Marcia Gay Harden in supporting roles.
It follows Ana and Christian as they must decide to rekindle their relationship,
this time with "no rules, no punishments, and no more secrets" terms.
Before the release of Fifty Shades of Grey in 2015, there was
high anticipation from fans for the sequel.
When the first film premiered at a special fan screening in New York City in
February 2015, development on the sequels promptly began.
By November 2015, Foley and Leonard were respectively hired to direct and
write both sequels, which would be shot back-to-back in 2016.
Principal photography was initially set to begin in Vancouver in June 2015.
However, it was later postponed due to delays in Leonard finishing the script.
Filming on Fifty Shades Darker and its sequel Fifty Shades Freed (2018) ultimately began on
February 9, 2016, in Paris and Vancouver, and concluded on April 11, 2016.
Danny Elfman, who had scored the first film, returned
to compose the score for its sequel.
Fifty Shades Darker premiered in Hamburg, Germany on February 7, 2017, and was
released in the United States on February 10, by Universal Pictures.
The film grossed $381 million worldwide against its $55 million budget, but received unfavorable reviews for
its screenplay, acting and narrative, though some of the performances received some praise.
At the 38th Golden Raspberry Awards, the film received nine nominations; including Worst Picture, Worst Actor (Dornan) and Worst
Actress (Johnson), and won two for Worst Prequel, Remake, Rip-off or Sequel, and Worst Supporting Actress (Basinger).
The film explores themes of based on novel or
book, boat, eroticism, kiss, sequel.
The tone is emotional.